

Stockholm, Sweden

(+46) 733 953018 | theaolivia.mail@gmail.com | https://theaolivia.dev | teaolivia | theaolivia

"I have a feeling tomorrow will be better is different from I resolve to make tomorrow better"

Summary

Software Engineer in Python based in Stockholm, Sweden and currently working for Klarna Bank AB. 2+ years experience specializing in the backend development and API design. I love getting involved in GitHub Open Source community and tinkering with Linux and OS X and enjoys to delivering best solutions to software products. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. Enjoying doing coding online judge such as uva.onlinejudge.org.

Skills_

Languages Python, JavaScript, Java, C++, PHP

Frameworks Django, Flask, React.js, Express.js, Node.js **Tools** Airflow, Kafka, TensorFlow, Git, GitHub

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL

Cloud Technologies AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Elastic BeanStalk, Google App Engine, Google Cloud SQL

Work Experience _____

Klarna Bank AB Stockholm, Sweden

PYTHON SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

January 2020-

- Assists recruiters with providing technical challenge for Lever from data to automation.
- · Automating repetitive recruiter tasks such as auto email welcoming service and auto correction for candidate data.
- Develops web apps mostly in Python3.8, PostgreSQL and deployed in AWS Lambda.

Self-Employed Bandung, Indonesia

FREELANCE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

January 2018 - December 2020

- · Provisioned an easily managable hybrid infrastructure(GCP + On-premise) utilizing some IaC(Infrastructure as Code) tools like Ansible or Ter-
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on TravisCI for containerized applications using Docker and Kubernetes.
- Designing an overall service architecture and pipelines of the e-Commerce infrastructure with the micro-services architecture.
- Designed and Implemented RESTful API microservices in Flask and in the serverless Google App Engines or AWS Lambda.
- Develops web apps mostly in React.js, Gatsby.js and Flask or Django.

rekruta.com Jakarta, Indonesia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

June 2016 - August 2016

- Developed Rekruta chrome extension for easier managing recruitment with stacks Javascript, JQuery, HTML and CSS built above Node.js.
- Developed a search engine as a product feature, search by attributes for more organized and faster sorting list of recruitees. Using Sails is and MongoDB queries and with Polymer 1.0 user interface.

Projects

viral.in Bandung, Indonesia

BACKEND AND INFRASTRUCTURE

June 2019

- Implemented RESTful API server for viralin with Flask and use React.js at front-end stack.
- · Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, TravisCI, and several AWS stack(Including EBS, Route 53, S3, Lambda, DynamoDB, Cognito, IAM), focusing on high-availability, high-scalability and less-maintainability.

The RAFFLES Project Bandung, Indonesia DATA ENGINEER

· A real-time English-Bahasa translation tool which users upload a document with no user credentials and return a translated document.

- · Using NLP tools (Prosa.ai's Syntax API for Bahasa and Stanford CoreNLP API for English) to generate POS-Tag and featured in Airflow.
- Designing real-time data pipelining using Apache Spark to stream the document and Kafka for queuing the input text of each document.
- Orchestrating Docker containers with Kubernetes and integrating CI/CD pipelines with TravisCI and GoCD and hosted with several AWS stack.

MAY 27, 2020 THEA OLIVIA YUSUF · RÉSUMÉ AquaAesthetic Bandung, Indonesia

CONTRIBUTOR April 2017

- My Object-Oriented Programming coursework while in college. Creating a simulator for aquarium.
- Implementing OOP concepts with Java and its interface with Java Spring and then use JUnit for unit testing.

Education

ITB (Bandung Institute of Technology)

Bandung, Indonesia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2011- April 2018

Courseworks: Algorithm and Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Distributed and Parallel Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning.

Honors & Awards

2017	Participant, ACM-ICPC 2017 Regional Contest	Jakarta, Indonesia
2016	Finalist, Facebook Indonesia Developer Challenge	Jakarta, Indonesia
2014	Finalist, GEMASTIK 7 Software Development Challenge	Jakarta, Indonesia